<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>akifmt</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on akifmt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akifmt.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blazor Expose a Feed as RSS</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-08-02-blazor-rssfeed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-08-02-blazor-rssfeed/</guid><description>Blazor Expose a Feed as RSS In this example, we will explore how to expose a feed as RSS using C# and the Blazor framework. We will create a controller that generates an RSS feed based on mock data.
RSS (Really Simple Syndication): RSS is a web feed format used to publish frequently updated content, such as blog posts, news headlines, or podcasts. It allows users to subscribe to a website&amp;rsquo;s content and receive updates in a standardized format.</description></item><item><title>Blazor EF Migrations with Multiple Providers</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-31-blazor-ef-multipledbproviders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-31-blazor-ef-multipledbproviders/</guid><description>Blazor Blazor Entity Framework Migrations with Multiple Providers This code demonstrates how to implement multiple database providers in a Blazor application using C#. It allows you to switch between different database providers, such as InMemory, SQLite, and SQL Server, based on the configuration settings.
Database Provider: Refers to the type of database being used, such as InMemory, SQLite, or SQL Server.
Connection String: A string that contains the necessary information to connect to a specific database.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Authentication and Authorization</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-30-blazor-authentication-authorization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-30-blazor-authentication-authorization/</guid><description>Blazor Authentication and Authorization This example represents a Blazor application that allows users to view a list of blog posts. The application uses ASP.NET Core and Blazor authentication and authorization to control access to the blog posts.
Before diving into the code, let&amp;rsquo;s understand some key concepts related to Blazor:
Blazor: Blazor is a web framework that allows developers to build interactive web UIs using C# instead of JavaScript. It enables developers to write code that runs on the client-side in the browser using WebAssembly or on the server-side using SignalR.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen CRUD</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-26-blazor-radzen-crud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-26-blazor-radzen-crud/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen CRUD In this article, we will explore the code for a Blazor page called &amp;ldquo;BlogPost&amp;rdquo;. This page displays a list of blog posts using a RadzenDataGrid component. We will go through the key concepts, code structure, and code examples to understand how this page works.
Before diving into the code, let&amp;rsquo;s understand some key concepts related to Blazor and RadzenDataGrid:
Blazor: Blazor is a web framework that allows developers to build interactive web UIs using C# instead of JavaScript.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen Search Comp.</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-21-blazor-radzen-searchcomponent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-21-blazor-radzen-searchcomponent/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen SearchComponent 1. Blazor Radzen List Page The code provided is a Blazor component that demonstrates how to fetch data from a service and display it in a RadzenDataList component. It also includes a custom search component that allows users to search for specific blog posts.
Blazor: Blazor is a web framework for building interactive client-side web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to write code in C# that runs on the client-side, eliminating the need for JavaScript.</description></item><item><title>Video Player in Blazor</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-20-blazor-videoplayer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2023-07-20-blazor-videoplayer/</guid><description>Video Player in Blazor This code provides a video player component in a Blazor application. It allows users to watch videos with controls and captions. The video player is customizable using the Plyr.io library.
Blazor: Blazor is a web framework that allows developers to build interactive web UIs using C# instead of JavaScript. It enables full-stack development with .NET. Plyr.io: Plyr.io is a JavaScript library that provides a customizable video player with a modern UI.</description></item><item><title>Programming</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2023-07-01-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2023-07-01-programming/</guid><description>Programming A programming language is a formal computer language designed to communicate instructions to a machine, particularly a computer. Programming languages can be used to create programs to control the behavior of a machine or to express algorithms. (Source: wikipedia)
Object Oriented Programming(OOP) Object Oriented Programming(OOP) is a programming paradigm based on the concept of objects, which may contain data, in the form of fields, often known as attributes; and code, in the form of procedures, often known as methods.</description></item><item><title>Node.js Deployment and Publishing on IIS - iisnode</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2019-08-08-iisnode.js/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2019-08-08-iisnode.js/</guid><description>Node.js Deployment and Publishing on IIS - iisnode
Tested on Windows Server 2016 x64 and IIS 10.0. All the requirements for different versions are the same, only the appropriate version for iisnode should be installed.
Requirements:
WebPlatformInstaller: WebPlatformInstaller IIS URL Rewrite extension: IIS URL Rewrite extension Node.js: node.js iisnode v0.22.1 x64 : iisnode v0.22.1 x64 After installation, the project should have &amp;ldquo;web.config&amp;rdquo;. The following config example can also be used with Express Framework.</description></item><item><title>Combining NodeJS Versions</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2019-02-10-nodejsfarklisurumleribiraradakullanma/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2019-02-10-nodejsfarklisurumleribiraradakullanma/</guid><description>Combining NodeJS Versions;
# Setup: npm install -g nvmw # nvmw install nvmw install v8.12.0 # installation of the versions to be used nvmw use v8.12.0 # Use the specific version # Use: nvmw help # help nvmw install [version] # Version install [version] nvmw uninstall [version] # Uninstall version [version] nvmw use [version] # Change version [version] nvmw ls # List of installed versions NodeJS Releases List: Versions</description></item><item><title>VNC Server on Google Cloud Ubuntu</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-09-21-googlecloudubuntuvnc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-09-21-googlecloudubuntuvnc/</guid><description>VNC Server on Google Cloud Ubuntu 16.04;
# Updates: sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade # Setup: sudo apt install xfce4 xfce4-goodies tightvncserver vncserver vncserver -kill :1 mv ~/.vnc/xstartup ~/.vnc/xstartup.bak nano ~/.vnc/xstartup xstartup content: #!/bin/bash xrdb $HOME/.Xresources startxfce4 &amp;amp; sudo chmod +x ~/.vnc/xstartup vncserver To connect via Windows: Download link</description></item><item><title>Torch, OpenCV Installation and Test</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-05-27-torchveopencvkurulum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-05-27-torchveopencvkurulum/</guid><description>OpenCV and Torch installation on Ubuntu 16.04;
# Updates: sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade shutdown -r 0 sudo apt-get install git #Torch Installation #Run in terminal in order: git clone https://github.com/torch/distro.git ~/torch --recursive cd ~/torch; bash install-deps; ./install.sh source ~/.bashrc source ~/.profile #OpenCV Installation: sudo apt-get install cmake git libgtk2.0-dev pkg-config libavcodec-dev libavformat-dev libswscale-dev 2015-12-21 VERSION 3.1 OpenCV for Linux/Mac cd ~ wget https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/archive/3.1.0.zip --no-check-certificate unzip 3.1.0.zip cd opencv-3.</description></item><item><title>Edit EPub Cover</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-05-02-epubcover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-05-02-epubcover/</guid><description>
The cover pages of some e-books do not appear on other devices due to incompatibility. The solution for this is caliber. It provides the opportunity to edit not only the cover page but also the content. Download link
To edit the cover page; It will be enough to edit the following line with the &amp;ldquo;Edit Metadata&amp;rdquo; option or add it if it does not exist.
&amp;lt;item id=&amp;#34;cover_image&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;cover.jpg&amp;#34; media-type=&amp;#34;image/jpeg&amp;#34;&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Game Theory - Prisoner's Dilemma and Nash Equilibrium</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-03-16-prisonersdilemmavenashdengesi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-03-16-prisonersdilemmavenashdengesi/</guid><description>Get two people caught. If one testifies against the other and the other remains silent, the witness will be released, and the party who chooses to remain silent will be sentenced to 20 years in prison. If both remain silent, they will be sentenced to 1 year each. If both testify against each other, they will each be sentenced to 5 years.
The optimal option of the two is to keep both silent.</description></item><item><title>shields.io</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-03-19-shields.io/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-03-19-shields.io/</guid><description>A tool for the ReadMe files of projects to display the project status in a nicer way. shields.io supports many tools used for project tracking. Travis, Jenkins and even Github allow badges to be added up to the release status of the project on SourceForce.</description></item><item><title>Linux Bash Commands</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-02-24-linuxbashkomutlari/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-02-24-linuxbashkomutlari/</guid><description>Active folder: pwd Appearance: ls &amp;#39;Detailed View Parameters: -l *detailed* -lrt *detailed* -d *folder* -r *read* -w *write* -x *execute*&amp;#39; Active Folder Change: cd &amp;lt;folder name&amp;gt; File Creation: touch &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt; Displayed: ctrl+k &amp;#39;delete to the right&amp;#39; echo &amp;#34;hello world&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;hello coders&amp;#34; &amp;gt; filename &amp;#39;Send output to file&amp;#39; echo $? &amp;#39;Returns the result of the last operation (0 successful)&amp;#39; cat filename &amp;#39;prints file contents&amp;#39; more filename &amp;#39;prints file contents&amp;#39; less filename &amp;#39;prints file contents&amp;#39; nano filename &amp;#39;opens with nano text editor&amp;#39; vim filename &amp;#39;opens with vim text editor&amp;#39; head -n 5 output-1.</description></item><item><title>VMware and Hyper-V Combine</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-02-22-hypervmwarebirlikte/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-02-22-hypervmwarebirlikte/</guid><description>To turn off Hyper-V; As administrator on cmd: bcdedit /set hypervisorlaunchtype off vmware available after reboot.
To turn Hyper-V back on As administrator on cmd: bcdedit /set hypervisorlaunchtype auto Hyper-V is available upon reboot.</description></item><item><title>Agile</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-02-20-agile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2017-02-20-agile/</guid><description>Agile Methodology is a practice-based method for modeling and documenting software systems effectively and efficiently.
Software projects are faced with the danger of failure due to improper use of resources, wrong prioritization and inaccurate understanding of customer demands throughout their lifecycle. According to The Standish Group&amp;rsquo;s 2009 Chaos Report, software projects fail at a rate of 68% worldwide. This has led large companies in Europe and America to try various methods to produce projects with higher productivity, and most companies have adopted Agile software development approaches, which they find most successful in management and practice.</description></item><item><title>What is Docker?</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-11-24-docker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-11-24-docker/</guid><description>What is Docker Docker is an open source project that deploy application. It works like a virtual machine, but better. Using a linux instance, it isolates itself from OS and works more secure. Docker defines itself like that on official website;
Docker containers wrap a piece of software in a complete filesystem that contains everything needed to run: code, runtime, system tools, system libraries – anything that can be installed on a server.</description></item><item><title>Android 7 Nougat</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-11-02-android7nougat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-11-02-android7nougat/</guid><description>
New features
Multi-window / running two apps on the same screen (The most important feature) New notification center Revamped settings menu Notifications settings have been enriched. We will now be able to prevent every notification from appearing. Added the ability to go to the relevant menu of the settings by long pressing the icons in the notification Refreshing battery graph</description></item><item><title>Monte Carlo Method</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-10-09-montecarlometodu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-10-09-montecarlometodu/</guid><description>Nedir: Rastgele sayılar kullanılarak sistemlerin modellenmesinde kullanılabilir. Sistemin kesin sonucunun olduğu bazı durumlarda, veya olmadığı tüm durumlarda uygulanabilir. Örnek sayısı doğru sonuçlar elde etmede büyük önem taşımaktadır. Pi sayısı hesaplama, yazı tura ve zar hesaplaması örnek gösterilebilir.
Örnek: C ile Yazı-Tura double rastgele(){ double r = (double) rand()/RAND_MAX; return r; } int main() { int i, tura, yazi, n; double r, p; printf(&amp;#34;deney sayisini girin: &amp;#34;); scanf(&amp;#34;%d&amp;#34;,&amp;amp;n); srand( time(NULL) ); for(tura=0, i=1; i&amp;lt;=n; i++){ r = rastgele(); if(r&amp;lt;0.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Remote Desktop Turkish Keyboard Problem</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-09-18-raspberrypiilerdcbaglantisi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-09-18-raspberrypiilerdcbaglantisi/</guid><description>
Problem: Raspbery Pi Remote Connection TR Keyboard Not Recognizing Solution: missing km-041f.ini file
Copy the km-041f.ini file to the /etc/xrdp/ directory on the Raspberry Pi. When xrdp is restarted, TR characters are no longer a problem.
The thing to note is that you must access the directory as root.
The step I followed; sudo pcmanfm on RasPi Copy the km-041f.ini file to /etc/xrdp/.
sudo service xrdp restart
Note: For those who have problems finding the file on the net, I downloaded it from this repo: Link</description></item><item><title>Application Sounds on Amazon AWS and Azure with Remote Desktop</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-08-22-rdcileawsveazurevpsuzerindevacileses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-08-22-rdcileawsveazurevpsuzerindevacileses/</guid><description>Since VPS devices on AWS or Azure do not have a real sound card, it is not possible to receive sound on these devices. The solution for this is VA, that is, virtual audio. Our convenient application solution is solved with VAC installation. The application creates a virtual sound driver and directs the sound to our device.
Problem: Voice over VPS Solution: Virtual Audio Cable 4.15 installation and Setup</description></item><item><title>INVICTUS, Internship in IT Security</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-08-03-invictusbilisimguvenlikstajyapmak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-08-03-invictusbilisimguvenlikstajyapmak/</guid><description>The company works on cyber security and security training. I also contacted my friend&amp;rsquo;s reference. The sincerity I saw from day one surprised me. I saw a full family relationship in the company, from management to employees. With the experienced team, they included them at every point by providing training on cyber security at a high-level security level, starting from scratch. The company is experienced in cyber security and even works towards becoming a world brand.</description></item><item><title>Playing Pokemon GO!</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-07-10-pokemongooynamak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/posts/2016-07-10-pokemongooynamak/</guid><description>A game that can be played on mobile platforms. The biggest innovation and feature is virtualized reality technology. Using real location information, it provides a better player experience, catching 722 Pokemon characters, trades and battles. The official introduction is as follows:</description></item><item><title>Bash Variables</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/notes/bash/basic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/notes/bash/basic/</guid><description> Variable NAME=&amp;#34;John&amp;#34; echo $NAME echo &amp;#34;$NAME&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;${NAME} Condition if [[ -z &amp;#34;$string&amp;#34; ]]; then echo &amp;#34;String is empty&amp;#34; elif [[ -n &amp;#34;$string&amp;#34; ]]; then echo &amp;#34;String is not empty&amp;#34; fi</description></item><item><title>Dotnet</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/notes/dotnet/gists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/notes/dotnet/gists/</guid><description> Startup.cs No image display bug fix appsettings.json Uploading Image</description></item><item><title>project1en</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/projects/project1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/projects/project1/</guid><description>Table of contents Table of contents Text Code Python C/C++ Bash Tables Text Some example text
Code Python def foo(): print (&amp;#34;This is a python function&amp;#34;) C/C++ void foo(){ prinf(&amp;#34;%s\n&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;This is a C function&amp;#34;) } Bash # This is a bash command cd dir &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo $PWD; # Return exit 0; Tables Pages Elements 1 Text 2 Code 3 Tables</description></item><item><title>project2en</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/projects/project2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/projects/project2/</guid><description>Table of contents Table of contents Text Code Python C/C++ Bash Tables Text Some example text
Code Python def foo(): print (&amp;#34;This is a python function&amp;#34;) C/C++ void foo(){ prinf(&amp;#34;%s\n&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;This is a C function&amp;#34;) } Bash # This is a bash command cd dir &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo $PWD; # Return exit 0; Tables Pages Elements 1 Text 2 Code 3 Tables</description></item></channel></rss>