<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>encapsulation on akifmt</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/tags/encapsulation/</link><description>Recent content in encapsulation on akifmt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akifmt.github.io/tags/encapsulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Association, Aggregation, Composition</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/programming/04-programming04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/programming/04-programming04/</guid><description>Association: A relationship where all objects have their own lifecycle and there is no owner. Aggregation: A specialised form of Association where all objects have their own lifecycle, but there is ownership and child objects can not belong to another parent object. Composition: A specialised form of Aggregation and we can call this as a “death” relationship. It is a strong type of Aggregation. Child object does not have its lifecycle and if parent object is deleted, all child objects will also be deleted.</description></item><item><title>What is Encapsulation (or Information Hiding)?</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/programming/03-programming03encapsulation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/programming/03-programming03encapsulation/</guid><description>The encapsulation is the inclusion-within a program object-of all the resources needed for the object to function, basically, the methods and the data. In OOP the encapsulation is mainly achieved by creating classes, the classes expose public methods and properties. A class is kind of a container or capsule or a cell, which encapsulate a set of methods, attribute and properties to provide its indented functionalities to other classes. In that sense, encapsulation also allows a class to change its internal implementation without hurting the overall functioning of the system.</description></item></channel></rss>