<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Identity on akifmt</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/categories/identity/</link><description>Recent content in Identity on akifmt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akifmt.github.io/categories/identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Role-based Authorization with Identity</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-10-blazor-radzen-.net8-role-based-authorization-with-identity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-10-blazor-radzen-.net8-role-based-authorization-with-identity/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Role-based Authorization with Identity Blazor: Blazor is a web framework for building interactive client-side web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows you to write code that runs on the client-side in the browser.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development tool for building web applications. It provides a visual interface for designing UI components and generating code.
.NET 8: .NET 8 is the latest version of the .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Identity Automatically Logout Timer</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-03-blazor-radzen-.net8-identity-automatically-logout-timer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-03-blazor-radzen-.net8-identity-automatically-logout-timer/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Identity Automatically Logout Timer Blazor: Blazor is a web framework for building interactive client-side web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to write code that runs on the client-side and interacts with the server-side.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development platform that provides tools and components for building web applications. It simplifies the development process by generating code and providing a visual interface for designing UI components.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Authentication &amp; Authorization with Identity</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-07-28-blazor-radzen-.net8-authenticationauthorization-with-identity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-07-28-blazor-radzen-.net8-authenticationauthorization-with-identity/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization with Identity Blazor: Blazor is a framework for building interactive web UIs using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to create web applications using .NET.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development tool that helps in building web applications quickly and efficiently.
.NET 8: .NET 8 is a software framework developed by Microsoft for building different types of applications, including web applications.</description></item></channel></rss>