<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Radzen on akifmt</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/categories/radzen/</link><description>Recent content in Radzen on akifmt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akifmt.github.io/categories/radzen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 DataGrid InCellEdit</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2025-07-20-blazor-radzen-.net8-datagrid-incelledit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2025-07-20-blazor-radzen-.net8-datagrid-incelledit/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 DataGrid InCellEdit Blazor: Blazor A framework for building interactive web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to create rich web UIs with a component-based architecture.
Radzen: Radzen A set of UI components for Blazor that simplifies the development of web applications. It provides a variety of controls, including DataGrids, which are essential for displaying and managing data.
.NET 8: .NET 8 is the latest version of the .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 DataGrid InLineEdit</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2025-07-05-blazor-radzen-.net8-datagrid-inlineedit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2025-07-05-blazor-radzen-.net8-datagrid-inlineedit/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 DataGrid InLineEdit Blazor: Blazor A framework for building interactive web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to create rich web UIs with a component-based architecture.
Radzen: Radzen A set of UI components for Blazor that simplifies the development of web applications. It provides a variety of controls, including DataGrids, which are essential for displaying and managing data. .NET 8: .NET 8 is the latest version of the .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Menu with Adaptive Behavior for Mobile and Desktop</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2025-06-01-blazor-radzen-.net8-menu-with-adaptive-behavior-for-mobile-and-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2025-06-01-blazor-radzen-.net8-menu-with-adaptive-behavior-for-mobile-and-desktop/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Menu with Adaptive Behavior for Mobile and Desktop Blazor: Blazor A framework for building interactive web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to create rich web UIs with a component-based architecture.
Radzen: Radzen A set of UI components for Blazor that simplifies the development of web applications. The Radzen Panel Menu is a versatile component that provides a collapsible menu structure.
.NET 8: .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Upgrade Radzen 4 to 5</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-11-blazor-radzen-.net8-upgrade-radzen-4-to-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-11-blazor-radzen-.net8-upgrade-radzen-4-to-5/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Upgrade Radzen 4 to 5 The process of upgrading the Radzen.Blazor package from version 4 to version 5 in a Blazor project targeting .NET 8.0. This upgrade is essential to leverage the latest features, improvements, and bug fixes provided by Radzen.
Information
Radzen Blazor Components v5 Changelog Track and review changes to Radzen Blazor Components v5.
More: https://blazor.radzen.com/changelog?theme=default
.csproj Update NuGet packages In the updated .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Role-based Authorization with Identity</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-10-blazor-radzen-.net8-role-based-authorization-with-identity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-10-blazor-radzen-.net8-role-based-authorization-with-identity/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Role-based Authorization with Identity Blazor: Blazor is a web framework for building interactive client-side web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows you to write code that runs on the client-side in the browser.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development tool for building web applications. It provides a visual interface for designing UI components and generating code.
.NET 8: .NET 8 is the latest version of the .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Identity Automatically Logout Timer</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-03-blazor-radzen-.net8-identity-automatically-logout-timer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-08-03-blazor-radzen-.net8-identity-automatically-logout-timer/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Identity Automatically Logout Timer Blazor: Blazor is a web framework for building interactive client-side web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to write code that runs on the client-side and interacts with the server-side.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development platform that provides tools and components for building web applications. It simplifies the development process by generating code and providing a visual interface for designing UI components.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Authentication &amp; Authorization with Identity</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-07-28-blazor-radzen-.net8-authenticationauthorization-with-identity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-07-28-blazor-radzen-.net8-authenticationauthorization-with-identity/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization with Identity Blazor: Blazor is a framework for building interactive web UIs using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to create web applications using .NET.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development tool that helps in building web applications quickly and efficiently.
.NET 8: .NET 8 is a software framework developed by Microsoft for building different types of applications, including web applications.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Google Maps</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-06-08-blazor-radzen-.net8-google-maps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-06-08-blazor-radzen-.net8-google-maps/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Google Maps Blazor: Blazor is a web framework for building interactive client-side web applications using C# instead of JavaScript. It allows developers to write code in C# and have it run directly in the browser.
Radzen: Radzen is a low-code development platform that provides tools and components for building web applications. It simplifies the development process by generating code and providing a visual interface for designing user interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Serilog Logging to Console, File and Database</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-05-29-blazor-radzen-.net8-serilog-logging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-05-29-blazor-radzen-.net8-serilog-logging/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Serilog Logging to Console, File and Database Logging: Logging is the process of recording events, messages, or exceptions that occur during the execution of an application. It helps developers understand the behavior of the application, diagnose issues, and track its performance. Logging is an essential aspect of software development and plays a crucial role in maintaining and troubleshooting applications.
Serilog: Serilog is a popular logging library for .</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Html Editor</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-05-15-blazor-radzen-.net8-htmleditor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-05-15-blazor-radzen-.net8-htmleditor/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Html Editor Blazor: Blazor is a framework for building interactive web UIs using C# instead of JavaScript. Radzen: Radzen is a suite of tools that provides UI components for Blazor applications. .NET 8: .NET 8 is the latest version of the .NET framework that supports Blazor development. Html Editor: An HTML editor is a tool that enables users to create, edit, and format HTML content.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Multiple Themes Dark and Light Mode</title><link>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-05-04-blazor-radzen-.net8-multiple-themes-dark-and-light-mode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akifmt.github.io/dotnet/2024-05-04-blazor-radzen-.net8-multiple-themes-dark-and-light-mode/</guid><description>Blazor Radzen .NET 8 Multiple Themes Dark and Light Mode We are implementing dynamic theme switching in a Blazor application using Radzen. The code allows users to switch between different themes (e.g., default, dark, humanistic, software, standard, material) based on their preference.
.NET 8: .NET 8 is a version of the .NET framework that provides developers with a platform to build various types of applications. It offers improved performance, security, and features for developing modern applications.</description></item></channel></rss>